我是杰森.西弗，是个心理医生
Hi, I'm Jason Seaver. I'm a psychiatrist.
过去15年里 我致力于解决患者的问题
I've spent the last 15 years helping people with their problems.
fitbbs chengse
我是麦姬.西弗
And I'm Maggie Seaver.
过去15年里，我一直围着孩子们转
I've spent the last 15 years helping our kids...
解决那些杰森也束手无策的问题
with problems even Jason wouldn't believe.
现在麦姬已重操旧业 在一家当地报社做记者
Now Maggie has gone back to work as a reporter for the local newspaper.
杰森把他的诊所搬到了家里
And Jason has moved his practice into the house...
这样就可以陪着孩子们了
so he could be there for the kids.
-他们是可爱的孩子 -大多时候都是
- They're great kids. - Most of the time.
但是有时…
And the rest of the time...
-反正你会喜欢他们的 -没错
- You'll love them anyway. - Yeah.
鬼才相信
Unbelievable.
(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E01 -= Pilot =- Subripped by zerox
夫人，放下锅铲 否则就搅你一下
All right, lady, drop that spatula or you're scrambled.
尽管放马过来
Go ahead. Make my day.
Well...
好像是我在搅你哦
I guess I showed you.
再搅一下
Show me more.
杰森，孩子们都在呢
Jason, the kids.
等下再亲他们
I can kiss the kids later.
我看过一篇文章 说夫妻都工作的家庭…
You know, I read an article that said that two-career couples...
尤其要注意保持…
should really make special effort to always remain...
活泼
frisky.
早饭的时候？
At breakfast?
早中晚饭
At all meals.
怎么，你们不会亲腻的吗？
What's the matter, you guys aren't getting enough?
麦克，小孩的这种言行 可是会挨揍的哦
Mike, a lot of kids would get smacked for a remark like that.
得了吧，老爸，你不能打我 你可是自由人道主义者
Come on, Dad, you can't hit me. You're a liberal humanist.
不包括意外情况
Could be an accident.
我真是求之不得
It could be a dream come true.
妈妈，我们干脆把凯罗卖掉 换台车载音响吧？
Mom, can't we sell Carol and get a tape deck for the Volvo?
麦克，你重新诠释了“草包”这个词
Mike, you give new meaning to the word "vacuous."
是吗？那它原来的意思是啥？
Oh, yeah? What was the old meaning?
懒得跟你说了
I rest my case.
本…
Ben. Ben.
什么这么好笑呢？
What's so funny, Ben?
菲莉丝.乔治又说错话了! [早间新闻主播]
That Phyllis George! She screwed up again!
宝贝，你在看什么呢？
Honey, what's that you're reading about?
这上面说，当宇宙膨胀时…
It says here that as the universe expands...
一切物质都会变得越来越老化和混沌
all matter is slowly degenerating into a state of total disorganization.
感谢上帝，我以为只有我才这样
Thank God. I thought it was just me.
你们晚上有啥节目？
Yeah, so, what are you guys doing tonight?
“汗之屋”？太棒了!
The House of Sweat? Yeah, great!
我迟点再打给你 好，拜
Hey, look, can I talk to you guys later? Yeah. Bye.
麦克，“汗之屋”是什么意思？
Mike, what is "The House of Sweat"?
就是…
Well... It's, you know...
高速公路旁新开的一家 未成年人舞厅
It's that new under-20 dance club on Jericho Turnpike.
听这名字挺不错的，老妈
Yeah, and it sounds like a great idea, Mom.
那是个安全，健康的 年轻人聚会场所
It's a safe, wholesome place for teens to congregate.
人聚得越多，脑子就越小
And the larger the group, the smaller their brains get.
别这样嘛，麦姬…
Come on, Maggie...
是啊，别这样嘛
Yeah, come on, Maggie.
对了，我该出去等校巴了
Yes. Well, time to go wait for that school bus.
动作快点的话没准还能在 无烟区抢到座位
You know, if I hurry, I can still get a seat in the non-smoking section.
-再见，宝贝 -妈妈再见
- Bye, sweetie. - Bye, Mom.
再见，本，我爱你
Bye, Ben. I love you.
再见，本
Later, Ben.
9点上班前 我还有点案头工作要做
I still have some paperwork to do before my 9:00 gets here.
如果你刚才意犹未尽 而且有丁点空闲的话…
And if you start feeling frisky and you have eight or 10 seconds before work...
你知道去哪找我
you know where to find me.
本，怎么还没走？ 你会误了校车的
Ben, what are you doing here? You'll miss the bus.
怎么了，宝贝？
What's the matter, honey?
爸爸没把我的胳膊肘治好
Dad didn't know how to do my elbow.
让我看看
Let me see.
爸爸做得很好 他给你贴了个超人创可贴
Dad did a great job on this cut. Superman Band-Aids, the works.
我明白了，他没有亲亲
I get it. He didn't kiss it.
没说“我爱你，小南瓜头”
And say, "I love you, little pumpkin head."
太不投入了
It was all so clinical.
妈妈，你非要回去工作吗？
Mom, how come you had to go back to work?
不是非去不可，是我想去
I didn't have to, Ben. I wanted to.
过来
Come here.
本，假如你在一所房子里…
Ben, imagine you had to spend...
闷了15年，哪也不准去
15 years in this house without ever going out to play.
你也会疯的，对吗？
You'd go crazy, wouldn't you?
不管你信不信 很多大人对工作也是这种态度
Well, believe it or not, a lot of grown-ups feel the same way about work.
是够惨的，妈妈
That's sick, Mom.
我知道这对我们大家都有影响
Ben, I know this has been a big change for all of us.
而且我对你也放不下心 因为你最小
And I worry about not being here for you, because, well, you're the youngest.
我对凯罗放不下心是因为…
And I worry about not being here for Carol...
她是女孩，女孩需要妈妈
because she's a girl and she needs her mother.
我不放心麦克是因为…
And I worry about not being here for Mike...
我怕他老是闯祸
to keep him from accidentally blowing something up.
而且，我对爸爸也放心不下…
And, believe me, I worry about leaving your father here...
因为他要应付你们三个小魔怪
to cope with all you monsters.
不要担心，妈妈 你这样会发疯的
You shouldn't worry so much, Mom. You'll make yourself crazy.
我爱你，小南瓜头
I love you, little pumpkin head.
我总是做同一个梦，大夫
It's always the same dream, Doc.
我在地铁里 一个女人坐在我对面
I'm on a subway and this woman sits across from me.
她长得很漂亮
This beautiful woman.
我看着她，她看着我
And I look at her. She looks at me.
我舔舔嘴
I lick my lips.
她也舔舔嘴
She licks her lips.
就这么舔下去
This goes on.
最后她凑过来，低声对我说…
Then, finally, she leans across, and she whispers to me:
“你的膝盖好大”
"You have huge knees."
这话啥意思呢，大夫？
Does that mean anything, Doc?
每人5块钱对口费
That should be good for about $5 apiece.
就到这里，沃特
Good visit, Walter.
别太过担心了，好吗？
And don't worry too much about this thing. Okay?
下周见，再见
See you next week. Bye-bye.
-爸，能跟你说句话吗？ -没问题
- Could I talk to you for a second, Dad? - Sure.
-到你办公室说 -好的
- In your office. - Sure.
-小孩子 -我吗？
- Kids. - Me?
对
Yeah.
你想跟我谈什么呢？
So you wanted to talk about something?
是的
Yeah.
最主要的是 向你表示这里一切安好
Mostly I just wanted to mention how smoothly things have been running...
自从你妻子回去上班 你在家里接待患者
since the wife went back to work and you moved your practice into the house.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
爸，我们一直都是朋友关系，对吧？
Dad, we've been friends now for a long time, right?
断断续续吧
Off and on, yeah.
断断续续，我喜欢这样
"Off and on." I love that.
老爸，还记得我今早说过的 那个舞厅吧？
See, Dad, you know that dance hall place that I mentioned this morning?
汗之屋？
The House of Sweat?
是的
Yeah.
杰里和我商量了一下，我们决定…
Jerry and I were talking and we decided...
杰里？
Jerry?
对，杰里.德利什
Yeah, Jerry Dellish.
他是我的老朋友，车技一流
He's an older friend of mine. Excellent driver...
学过两年驾驶
with two years of driver's ed.
学过两年驾驶？
Two years of driver's ed?
是的，第一节课时他撞上了一条狗
Yeah. See, in his first class he ran over a dog.
不过打那以后，他车开得很棒
But he drove beautifully after that.
那只是只微不足道的鲁莽小狗
We're talking about one tiny, reckless little dog here, Dad.
-算它倒霉 -是啊
- Tough break. - Yeah.
总之，我们想今晚去那里玩会儿
So, anyway, I was thinking that maybe we could go down there tonight.
杰里开车，所以不用你接送
Jerry would drive so you wouldn't have to do...
你老妈会怎么说？
What would your mother say?
妈妈？
Mom?
我想她会说…
I guess she would say...
那个词应该怎么说来着？
What's the phrase I'm looking for here, Dad?
-没门 -是的，就这个
- "No"? - Yeah, that's it.
我想我是去不了的了，是吗？
I guess that means I can't go, right?
我只是不想你每次跟我套近乎…
Well, it just means I don't like you coming in here...
都是带有目的
and trying to get away with something.
我不希望我们的关系变成这样
That's not the relationship I want to have with you.
对不起，爸爸
I'm sorry, Dad.
好吧，听我说
All right, now, look.
现在家里我说了算 我们可按我的方针办事
Now that I'm in charge at home, we can try things my way.
太棒了!
All right!
你还不知道我的方针是啥呢
You don't even know what my way is.
当然知道，更多的自由
Sure I do, Dad. It's a Sinatra song.
你的领悟能力真强，麦克
You're walking a fine line here, Mike.
好吧，我们得作个约定
Okay, look, here's the deal.
我会给你更多的自由
I'll give you a little more freedom.
但你也要保证承担更多的责任
You've got to promise me a lot more responsibility.
没问题，老爸 我发誓，我可以全面承担责任
Hey, no problem, Dad. I swear, I am ready for total responsibility.
麦克，连我都不敢说全面承担责任
Mike, I'm not ready for total responsibility.
你说得对，对不起
You're right. Sorry.
好了，那你玩得开心点吧
Okay. You go out and have a good time.
记住我们刚才说的话
Just remember what we talked about.
绝对记住，谢谢爸爸 我保证
Absolutely, Dad! Thanks, I promise.
对了，妈妈咋办？ 她要是发火咋办？
Wait. What about Mom? What if she's mad?
麦克，你妈又不是魔王 我跟她说，她会通情达理的
Mike, your mom's not an ogre. I'll talk to her. She'll understand.
你让他什么？
You let him do what?
麦姬，他都15岁了
Maggie, he's 15 years old now.
15岁又怎样？
So he's 15.
这简直毫无道理
It's completely arbitrary...
随便找个年纪划分孩子的成熟兴否
to just pick an age like that and say that's when a kid is mature.
莫扎特15岁时便写了七部交响乐
You know, by the time Mozart was 15, he'd written seven symphonies.
那是因为莫扎特的父亲 没让他去“汗之屋”
That's because Mozart's father didn't let him go to The House of Sweat.
他和谁一起去？
Who did he go with?
不知道，好像一个叫杰里.德利什的
I don't know, some kid. Jerry Dillish, Dellish.
杀狗大王德利什？
Jerry "Dog-Killer" Dellish?
麦姬，他不过是撞了只狗狗而已
Maggie, he hit one dog.
可他来回撞了四次
Yeah, but he hit it four times.
好吧…
Okay, well...
麦克又不是杰里
Mike isn't Jerry.
而且孩子需要一定的自由 来培养责任感
And a kid needs some freedom in order to learn responsibility.
杰森，我知道你信奉“人类潜力无限”
Jason, I know you believe in this "unlimited human potential"...
这种废话
stuff.
这句话对你的患者也许适用
And that's great for your patients.
-但要是用在… -我们的孩子
- But when it comes... - To our own children...
-我相信人都有… -原罪
...I believe in original... - Sin.
原罪
Sin.
也许我真不该回去上班
I don't know. Maybe I shouldn't have gone back to work.
行了，麦姬，别这么说
Now, come on, Maggie, don't say that.
你花了15年时间建立个家庭 你理应得到上班的奖励
You took 15 years off to raise a family, and you deserve to go back to work now.
但你该给我和孩子们多点信任
You just have to have a little more faith in me and the kids.
也许你说得对
Maybe you're right.
这还用说
Of course I'm right.
我们不该担心，而是应该庆祝…
We shouldn't be worrying, we should be celebrating...
所以，请恕小生冒昧 现已将一瓶冰镇香槟…
which is why I've taken the liberty of placing some chilled champagne...
置于床边小桶
in a little bucket beside the bed.
还在床上铺好了一张缎子床单
Slipped some satin sheets on the old bouncer.
缎子床单？你？
Satin sheets? You?
是的
Yeah.
店里的营业员还给我看了一对夫妇…
The guy in the store showed me some "before" and "after" pictures...
睡这张床单前后的照片
of a couple who tried them.
他们看上去很满足
They looked very satisfied.
本和凯罗咋办？
What about Ben and Carol?
我在他们的汽水里下了点安眠药
Well, I slipped some sleeping pills into their Gatorade.
他们会睡上3个星期
They'll be asleep for about three weeks.
杰森!
Jason!
我没有真放，不过他们的确眯了 我们可以…
Well, I didn't really. But they are... And we can...
你好，对，我是杰森.西弗
Hello? Yeah, this is Jason Seaver.
不，你一定找错人了 你先去脱衣服
No, you must be looking for someone else. Take your clothes off.
不会的，我家的麦克才15岁 开车的应该不是他
No, our Mike is only 15, so he wouldn't be driving a car.
明白了
I see.
他说什么？
What did he say?
他说“所以你家麦克才会在我们监狱里”
He said, "That's why your Mike is in our jail."
你犯啥事了，小鬼？
What are you in for, kid?
我…
I...
我杀人，想看他怎么挂掉
I killed a man just to watch him die.
你呢？
You?
没付停车费
Unpaid parking tickets.
糟了，我妈来了!
Oh, no, it's my mom!
别激动，麦姬 还不知道实际情况哪
Come on, Maggie, we don't even know the facts yet.
我是说，和警察较点小劲…
I mean, it's not so unusual for a teenage boy...
在青少年里并不那么少见
to have a minor run-in with the police.
有些警察本身就够横的
Some of these guys can be real macho head-bangers.
嗨，要不要来杯热可可？ 我刚弄了一壶
Hiya, you folks care for some hot cocoa? I just made a fresh pot.
我们是西弗夫妇 你们关了我们儿子
Look, we're the Seavers. You've locked up our son.
一位警官声称他在开车
An officer claimed he was driving a car.
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
我们是在“汗之屋”的停车场捉到他的
We picked him up in The House of Sweat parking lot.
他开着车转了12分钟的圈
He'd been driving in circles for approximately 12 minutes.
一个15岁的孩子 拿朋友的车过一下手瘾
Okay, so a 15-year-old boy drives his friend's car around the lot a few times.
我有没说到他还刮花了一辆警车？
Did I mention he sideswiped a police car on the way out?
他什么？
He what?
他像剥橘子一样 把保险杠给掀掉了
He tore that bumper off like he was peeling an orange.
值350美圆的橘子
A $350 orange.
嗨，爸妈，你们起色不错嘛
Hiya, Dad, Mom. You look good tonight.
你看起来年轻多了
You look young.
出来吧，儿子
Come on, son.
妈，爸，这位是杰里
Mom, Dad, this is Jerry.
这种情形是挺难看出我俩的友情
I guess it's kind of hard to see the basis of our friendship, huh?
我只知道，他有种旁若无人的气质
I don't know. He has a certain carefree charm.
你应该看看他清醒时的样子
You should see him when he's sober.
麦克，罚你两个月不准出门
Mike, you will be grounded for two months.
两个月？
Two months?
-爸，快跟妈讲讲道理啊？ -讲过了，麦克
- Dad, can't you talk to her? - Oh, I did, Mike.
本来只要一个月的
Originally, it was one month.
这么说你加了一个月
Dad, that means you added a month.
这下没辙了吧？
Nothing gets by you, does it?
爸，你说你会跟她说…
Dad, you said you'd talk to her...
该死，麦克 你说你会负起责任的!
Damn it, Mike, you said you could act responsibly!
我现在不想再听到你唧唧歪歪，明白？
Now I don't want to hear another word out of you! Is that clear?
哇哦
- Whoa. - Whoa.
真是个浪漫的夜晚
Oh, yeah, our romantic evening.
看来没用过缎子床单的人真可能会…
Anyone who's not used to satin sheets could easily have an accident...
麦姬，别跟我说教了
Maggie, don't patronize me. Okay?
我那该死的睡衣在哪？
And where the hell are my pajamas?
对不起，我也不大确定在哪
Gee, I'm sorry. I'm really not sure.
你是不是觉得我连一套…
You wouldn't think it'd be so damn tough to keep tabs...
睡衣睡裤都管教不好？
on a pair of pajamas around here.
杰森，我不明白你为啥这么生气
Jason, I don't understand why you're so upset.
他又不是第一次闯祸了
I mean, it's not like this is the first time he's screwed up.
谁闯祸了？
Who screwed up?
麦克啊
Mike.
谁说麦克了？ 我生气是因为找不到睡衣
Who said anything about Mike? I'm upset because I can't find my pajamas.
我只不过一时没盯住自己的睡衣…
I mean, if you just left a pair of pajamas around...
转眼间这么一大件睡衣…
and these are big pajamas I'm talking about...
就这么人间蒸发掉了
And to think that they just vanished into thin air...
这能不让人恼火吗？
Well, wouldn't you be pretty upset?
的确也是，不过话说回来 我倒很喜欢你生气时的样子
Absolutely. In fact, I'm amazed at the way you're holding together.
怎么了？
What?
我从没见过爸爸气到不想说话的
I've never seen Dad actually too mad to talk.
多谢你的支持 我感觉自己已经洗心革面了
Thanks for your support. You know, I feel like a new man now.
对不起
I'm sorry.
其实也没那么糟啦
Look, it's not so bad.
没准过了一年后 他回想起这件事时还会笑呢
I bet, in a year, he'll look back at this whole thing and laugh.
也许是暗地里笑
Okay, maybe chuckle.
好吧，我承认
Okay, I admit it.
我生气是因为麦克
I'm upset with Mike.
Oh?
你不气吗？
Aren't you?
当然，我气炸了
Absolutely. I'm furious.
不过我对他以前干的几件事更生气
But no more furious than I've been at him a dozen other times before.
他还是个孩子 你还能要求他怎样？
I mean, he's a kid, Jason. What did you expect?
可他曾坐在我跟前信誓旦旦说…
Yeah, but he sat not 3 feet away from me and he said:
“爸，我发誓，我会全面负起责任”
"Dad, I swear it, I'm ready for total responsibility."
杰森，连你都不能负起全部责任
Jason, you are not ready for total responsibility.
面对现实吧，这孩子15岁了
I mean, face it, the boy is 15.
他是荷尔蒙驱动的闯祸机器
He's a hormone with feet.
我知道，但总有一天 他会长大成人的
I know, but someday that hormone will be a man.
我希望他到时能有点责任感
And I want that man to have a sense of responsibility.
去跟他谈谈
Go talk to him.
不谈你是睡不着的了
You won't sleep if you don't.
别担心，我会继续寻找睡衣
Don't worry. I'll continue the search for the pajamas.
干嘛？
What?
你睡着了
You were asleep.
睡着了？是睡着了
I was? I was.
这么说那只是场梦
And it was a dream.
你还在生气？
You're still angry?
爸，我知道这不是理由 但杰里的车确实很难控制
Hey, Dad, I know this is no excuse, but Jerry's car handles really badly.
我是看到杰里有点喝醉后 才不让他开车的
And I was the one who decided Jerry was too drunk to drive.
麦克，他醉到不省人事
Mike, he was unconscious.
我知道
I know.
你看到他醉成那样时 你应该怎么做？
What are you doing with a kid who drinks like that?
应该给你电话
I should've called you.
那为啥没打？
Why didn't you?
爸，那里有很多女孩…
Well, Dad, there was these girls there...
当然，不希望她们知道你有家长
Of course. Wouldn't want them to think you had parents.
麦克，如果我不能信任你 你觉得我们的关系会走向何方？
Mike, what kind of a relationship are we going to have if I can't trust you?
不知道，也许我是个闯祸星 也许你不该信任我
I don't know. I guess I'm just a jerk. Maybe you shouldn't trust me.
这个当然也是方向之一
That's certainly one way to go.
我爸和我就选择了这个方向
That's the way my father went with me.
我曾经想，如果我有儿子 一定不会走这条路
I guess I hoped that when I had a son it would be different.
我知道，老爸
I know, Dad.
麦克，我想你已经忘了
Mike, you probably don't remember this, but...
你三周大的时候…
when you were 3 weeks old...
我带你去看大都会的开垒
I took you to the Mets home opener.
抱着你摇啊摇
Cradled you in my arms.
直到唐.克伦登…
Up comes Donn Clendenon.
在第12局将球击出左野外的 广告牌赢得比赛
Hits a shot off the left-field scoreboard to win it in the 12th.
我紧紧抱着你
I hugged you real tight...
高兴地跳着
jumping up and down.
然后你就…
And you...
吐在你的棒球头盔里了
you threw up in your complimentary Mets batting helmet.
对不起，爸爸
I'm sorry, Dad.
是我的错
It was my fault.
我不该让你舔我手指上的啤酒
I never should've let you suck that beer off my finger.
不，爸爸，我说今晚对不起
No, Dad, I meant about tonight. I'm sorry.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
爸，我已经努力了，真的
You know, Dad, I try. I really try.
但有的时候…
But sometimes...
也不知道怎么回事 我就会做出点蠢事来
almost without warning, I just find myself doing something really stupid.
就像是一种无法控制的冲动？
Sort of an uncontrollable impulse?
没错
Yeah.
或者是这样，你知道自己 在做一件坏事…
Or is it more like you think you're doing something really stupid...
你估计一下免受惩罚的几率
and then you weigh your chances of getting away with it...
如果几率大于10%，你就干
and if they're better than 10%, you go for it.
是啊
Yeah!
所以你才会被禁闭两个月
That's why you're grounded for two months.
是啊
Yeah.
也许这话会让你好过点 我年轻时也干过荒唐的事
Well, if it makes you feel any better, I did some pretty lame-o things in my day.
-你？ -是的
- You? - Yeah.
譬如呢？
Like what?
记得我16岁的时候…
Like I remember when I was 16...
我和几个哥们有天晚上开车乱转…
me and some buddies, we drove around town one night...
向每个人露屁股 [Moon(月亮)：亦有朝某人露屁股之意]
mooning everybody.
我们甚至向市长夫人露屁股
We even mooned the mayor's wife.
真的？
You, Dad?
我们因非法露体而被捕
Yeah, we got arrested for indecent exposure.
不过还是把我们放了
Had to let us off though.
市长夫人拒绝指认是哪个屁股
Mayor's wife refused to make an identification.
-真的？ -能不能别这种语气？
- You, Dad? - Will you stop saying that?
妈妈知道这事吗？
Does Mom know about this?
这还用说
Are you kidding?
你以为我们怎么认识的？
How do you think we met?
好样的，老爸
All right, Dad.
老爸，你现在还有做蠢事的冲动吗？
Hey, Dad, do you ever get the urge to do dumb stuff now?
没有了，麦克
No, I don't, Mike.
成年人的区别就在于此
I think that's what being an adult is all about.
Oh.
好了，晚安，老爸
Well, all right. Good night, Dad.
晚安，儿子
Good night, son.
Hey.
再回来一下
Come back in here for a sec.
三个孩子唱的是 英文“月亮”(moon）有“露屁股”之意
谢谢观赏
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.04.01